

State College, PA 16801

■ 2022159621 | yjh5219ii@gmail.com | Wear November 09, 1993 | In https://github.com/Technicoloriii | In

https://www.linkedin.com/in/%E7%84%B0-%E9%83%9D-464350265/

Personal Profile

I'm a Ph.D. candidate in Pennsylvania State University planning to graduate and get my Ph.D. degree in November, 2023. My research interests are mostly public economic-involved topics, including fiscal federalism, public goods and public economics, governmental bargaining and taxation policy.

Education

Pennsylvania State University

State College, America

The Doctor of Philosophy (PhD)

Sept 2019 - Current

- · Working as a Research Assistant
- Working as a Adjunct Professor
- Courses: Public Administration, Public Policy, Network Analysis, Public Management Theory, Advanced Microeconomics Theory, Advanced Macroeconomics Theory, Advanced Econometrics, Real Analysis, Bayesian Econometrics, Industrial Organization, Public Economics, Public Finance

The Johns Hopkins University

Washington D.C, America

Master of Science in Economics

Sept 2017 - June 2019

- · Graduated with Distinction
- Courses: Stochastic Process, Topology, Ordinary Differential Equation, Partial Differential Equations, Financial Economics, Hedge Fund Market

Central University of Finance and Economics

Beijing, China

Bachelor in Accounting and Taxation

Apr 2012 - Apr 2016

- GPA top 15%
- Courses: Accounting, Intermediate Accounting, Managerial Accounting, Finance, Money and Banking, Financial Management, Auditing, Taxation Theory, Advanced Mathematics, Linear Algebra, Statistics, Probability Theory

Work Experience

Weifang Municipal Bureau of Statistics

Shandong, China

Intern

Dec 2015 - Jun 2016

- Collaborated with a four-person team to develop a statistical report on industrial organization in Weifang City, using python and R studio to generate necessary graphs and charts.
- Teamwork with 5 group members to generate an analysis of Weifang Census data
- Technical Skills: R studio and Python with PyTorch, NumPy, Matplotlib, Pandas, SK-learn.

Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Weifang

Shandong, China

Intern

Mar 2016 - Jun 2016

- Work with 10 members in Risk Control Department to analyze the data in the note book, estimate the conditions of companies, generate the evaluation report and control the credit risk.
- Technical Skills: Office, Markdown.

Guotai Junan (Shanghai) Securities

Shanghai, China

New Energy Industry Analysist

Feb 2023 - Current

• Working as a industrial researcher and using professional software like Wind or Bloomberg to independently generate the survey report on new energy industry in China. The topics I write include: the Water electrolysis hydrogen production industry Energy storage industry Mincluding pre-charge energy storage and household energy storage MAI industry energy consumption evaluation (using Chatgpt as an example) etc

Teaching Experience

Purdue University

Beijing, China

Teaching AssistantProfessor: Frank Kane

Jun 2018 - Sep 2018

Jun 2018 - Sep 2018

• Course: Accounting

Course. Accounting

Purdue University

Beijing, China

Teaching AssistantProfessor: Frank Kane

Course: Managerial Accounting

AUGUST 18, 2023

Johns Hopkins University

Teaching Assistant

Baltimore, America Sep 2017 - Jun 2018

· Professor: Lixiong Li

· Course: Econometrics

Pennsylvania State University

State College, America

Sep 2020 - Jun 2021

Teaching Assistant

• Professor: Kalyan Chatterjee

• Course: Microeconomics

Pennsylvania State University

Adjunct Professor

State College, America

Sep 2022 - Dec 2022

• Course: Introductory Game Theory **Pennsylvania State University**

Adjunct Professor

• Course: Introductory Statistics

State College, America

Sep 2022 - Dec 2022

University Projects

The Reform of Consumption Tax on Refined Oil Products

Beijng, China

Jan 2015 - Dec 2015

Central University of Finance and Economics

· Professor in charge: Yanfeng Bai

- Analysing data from 2008 to 2015 to discover patterns such as trends, correlations, and probabilities.
- · Discuss the pros and cons of the reform on tax policy in terms of the efficiency and political intention mathematically
- Technical Skills: Tableau, Stata, Office, LaTeX.
- Soft Skills: Time Management, Teamwork, Presentation skills, Report writing.

Credit Risk Modeling and Validation in Real Estate Market

Washington DC, America

Johns Hopkins University

Nov 2021 - Dec 2021

- Professor in charge: Sang-Sub Lee
- · Analysing data from 2008 to 2015 to discover patterns such as trends, correlations, and probabilities.
- Technical Skills: Python with Pandas, matplotlib, Seaborn. Latex. Matlab.
- **Soft Skills:** Model Construction, Writing, Data Analysis

Governmental Accounting and the Management, Discussion and Analysis Section: An **Exploratory Study of Understandability**

State College, America

Pennsylvania State University

Dec 2019 - Jan 2022

- Professor in charge: Odd.Stalebrink
- · Go through literature to generate a comprehensive literature review. Design a fixed effect model to conduct a longitudinal analysis
- Technical Skills: Stata. Latex
- Soft Skills: Model Construction, Writing, Data Analysis, Literature Reading and Summary

Bargaining with timing of information acquisition

State College, America

Pennsylvania State University

Jan 2020 - Dec 2022

- · Professor in Charge: Kalyan Chatterjee
- Go through and evaluate the mathematical proof developed by Dr Chatterjee, compare with the existing theoretical model
- Technical Skills: Latex
- Soft Skills: Model Construction, Literature Reading and Summary

Consumer Surplus of Alternative Payment Methods

State College, America

Pennsylvania State University

Jan 2021 - Dec 2022

- · Professor in Charge: David Argente
- · Data collecting, data wash and analysis, construct a difference in difference model to do a longotudinal analysis on consumer data.
- Technical Skills: Python, Stata, R, NodeXL
- Soft Skills: Model Construction, Data Analysis, Literature Reading and Summary

Skills

Programming Python (Pandas, PyTorch, NumPy, Scikit-learn. etc.), R(ggplot2), Stata, Matlab,

Miscellaneous ŁTFX(Overleaf or VScode), Tableau, Microsoft Office, Markdown, CorelDRAW, NodeXL, Wind and Bloomberg Terminal

Soft Skills Time Management, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Documentation, Engaging Presentation.

Student Achievements

AUGUST 18, 2023

2012	688/750 , College Entrance Exam	China
2017	327/340 , Graduate Record Examinations (GRE)	China
2017	110/120, TOEFL	China
2018	Level 1, Chartered Financial Analyst (CFA)	America
2018	2 of 6 subjects passed, Chinese Certified Professional Accountants (CPA)	China
2019	Full Scholarship, Pennsylvania State University	America

Publications.

CENTRAL AND LOCAL GOVERNMENTAL FISCAL BARGAINING UNDER FISCAL FEDERALISM—AN ANALYSIS WITH ASYMMETRIC SETTING

NATIONAL TAX JOURNAL

Condition: Revise and Resubmit

Author

POLITICAL PARTY CONTROL AND INTERGOVERNMENTAL TRANSFER UNDER FISCAL FEDERALISM

PUBLIC FINANCE REVIEW

Condition: Revise and Resubmit

Co-Author with Dr Odd Stalebrink

FLYPAPER EFFECT IN VARIOUS FIELDS: AN THEORETICAL INFERENCE AND BIBLIOGRAPHY EVIDENCE

PUBLIC FINANCE REVIEW

Condition: Revise and Resubmit

Author

GRANTS IN AID ON SUBNATIONAL'S TAX COLLECTION BEHAVIOR: AN PANEL DATA EMPIRICAL EVIDENCE

FEDERALISM AND FORMAL THEORY

Condition: Revise and Resubmit

Author

Working Papers

BUDGET PERSIST UNDER ASYMMETRIC INFORMATION INTERGOVERNMENTAL TRANSFER

with Yiqun Tong

Conference and Presentation Proceedings

AMERICAN SOCIETY FOR PUBLIC ADMINISTRATION CONFERENCE—PUBLIC FINANCE PANEL

Washington D.C, Nov 2019

Political Party Control and Intergovernmental Transfer under Fiscal Federalism—a Longitudinal Study

Presenter

NORTHEAST CONFERENCE ON PUBLIC ADMINISTRATION CONFERENCE—PUBLIC FINANCE PANEL

New York, Mar 2020

Political Party Control and Intergovernmental Transfer under Fiscal Federalism—a Longitudinal Study

Presenter

AMERICAN SOCIETY FOR PUBLIC ADMINISTRATION CONFERENCE—PUBLIC FINANCE PANEL

San Diego, Nov 2021

Fiscal Behavior of Central and Local Governments under Asymmetric Setting—a Game Theory Model Setting

Presenter

AMERICAN SOCIETY FOR PUBLIC ADMINISTRATION CONFERENCE—PUBLIC FINANCE PANEL

Online, Oct 2022

August 18, 2023

Grants in Aid on Subnational's Tax Collection Behavior: an Panel Data Empirical Evidence

Presenter

PENN STATE IO BROWNBAG

State College, Fall 2019–Spring 2022

Presenter

APPLIED MICRO SEMINAR

State College, November 2022

Presenter

Interests_____

Cooking I love cooking. I am an expert in most Chinese-style cooking.

Soccer

I was a member of school soccer team in Central University of Finance and Economics and competing with other universities in

Beijing in China University Football League(CUFL). Now I play for fun occasionally and I'm a huge fan of Arsenal FC.

Swimming I started swimming when I was 12. Going through submerged things while holding my breath was the most exciting part.

Languages _____

English Professional proficiency **Chinese** Native proficiency